(Music: "It Takes A Lot To
Know A Man"" by Damien Rice)
"What are you so afraid to lose?"
"What is it you're thinking
that will happen if you do?"
"What are you so afraid to lose?"
"What is it you're thinking
that will happen if you do?"
"What are you so afraid to lose?"
(The music fades.)
I still need a signature,
Mr. Albrecht. Here.
Take care out there.
Goodbye forever!
Yeah, fuck you too.
(Somber music)
Mr. Albrecht?
Jörg Albrecht?
- Ms. Bittner?
We had talked on the phone.
Go ahead, get in.
You can put your
bag on the back seat.
Thank you.
(The engine is started.)
(Soft, tense music)
Can I smoke?
Please not in the car.
You can drop me off
in the Leonhard district.
At the Eros Center, please.
So I'll show you your apartment.
From there, you can then
attend to your own needs.
(Dark, atmospheric music)
Here, in this building?
- Yes.
(Soft, tense music)
I know where I know you from.
From the trial.
What are you doing here?
(She breathes heavily.)
(Dark music)
(Crows cawing)
(Harsh, eerie music)
I am a doctor.
But being a doctor also
means I know anatomy very well.
With nerve points,
with pain.
The thing is simple:
Tell me who the other one was.
The name.
The name!
- The name.
Please tell us the name.
Tell us!
Help! Help!
Help!
(distantly:) Help!
What's the other one's name?
- Fuck you!
(Ominous music)
(quietly:) The name!
They'll kill me
if I say it.
(Heavy breathing.)
What's the other one's name?
- He'll kill me!
He'll kill me,
don't you get it?
(Eerie music)
What is that?
- You don't need to be afraid.
You'll tell us the name ...
the name!
What is that, what's in the syringe?
- The name!
It's not that simple!
What's in it?
- The name!
(Man:) We're seeing this through.
The name, the name!
- He'll kill me!
The name!
- What's in it?
- What's in the syringe?
The name!
(shouting:) The name,
the name, the name!
(whispering:) Stefan
Freund. Stefan Freund.
Stefan Freund.
But you didn't hear it from me, okay?
You didn't hear it from me!
We'll check that.
We'll check that, and
if you lied, we'll kill you.
I didn't lie!
Freund was back then with
the Devils in Reuttlingen.
Please, I've already paid for it!
I've already paid!
(schreit:) Ouch, stop it! Stop it!
I'm not like that anymore!
Please! Please ...
(He sobs.)
Mareike wanted to live, too.
I'm not like that anymore!
Stop it!
(Shrill, eerie music)
(Sobbing)
(Kettle whistles.)
(Pop music from the radio)
(Rhythmic pop music)
Dad?
- Hm?
Sabine's having her
birthday this weekend.
I need to take a break.
- At her parents' weekend house.
And everyone's staying over.
I need a sleeping bag, too.
What does that mean?
I haven't said yes yet.
Please! I'm not a
little girl anymore!
That's the whole point.
Do you know how embarrassing that is,
when I have to say,
that I'm not allowed to come along?
Did Sabine only
invite girls?
I don't know. Yeah ... no?
What now?
- Yeah, there are boys there too.
And Leon.
Leon? How old is he?
- 14.
I'd like to get to
know him first.
The party is today!
No way!
You just have to make it work somehow.
I don't know how either.
I'll ask Mom.
- She's not back until tomorrow.
Then I'm just going
without your permission.
You will not!
You will not,
you mustn't!
Come!
(Rhythmic pop music)
(Cell phone rings.)
Good morning, Sebastian.
- "Morning, Thorsten."
"Made it through the night shift?"
- I could rip trees out of the ground.
"Very good. We have a client."
"Kluge, corner of Rothenwaldstraße."
- Which number?
"You'll see. See you in a bit."
The guy is called Abdella al-Hamadı,
the other one Michael ...
Morning!
- Morning.
Morning, gentlemen.
- Morning, Dr. Vogt.
So, you're doing
the photos first? Okay.
In here?
- Yes, in there.
The garbage man Abdella al-Hamadi
found him, bin number six.
Was he already dead?
- Yes, he was already dead.
Rigor mortis is in the jaw, neck
and in the upper
extremities to be detected.
So, the time of
death was last night?
Yes, about ten to
twelve hours ago.
"One morning you
no longer wake up."
"The birds sing, as
they always sang."
"Nothing changes this course
of the day, only you have gone."
Goethe. I can only tell you
more about the cause of death later.
Did anyone see that
this garbage man - what's his name?
Abdella al-Hamadi.
- ... had found him?
Yes, his colleague, Michael Petro.
He saw it.
What's interesting: This is
Jörg Albrecht.
He had papers on him.
Was released from JVA Stammheim
yesterday.
What was he in for?
Rape resulting in death.
(Soft, dark music)
The footage here
is so distorted,
that the perpetrator, who had kidnapped
and abused the girl,
could not be identified.
So the perpetrator thought.
But the colleagues at the LKA
managed to
digitally reverse this alteration
Albrecht.
- Yes.
He came from a broken home,
was himself a victim of abuse
and, um, was noticed as a teenager
for animal cruelty.
What exactly?
- Small animals.
Then he seriously injured a mare
with a knife. Youth prison.
That's when he met his new
friends.
With the Devils.
'A motorcycle club,
there isn't one anymore.
(Soft, eerie music)
(Doorbell)
(doorbell)
Hello!
- Hello.
A package for Mr. Freund?
- But it's to be handed over in person.
He won't be back until this evening.
Retraining.
Where's the retraining?
- At ... at ... Henneling.
That's the automotive
supplier in Obertürkheim?
Yes ... Yes, exactly.
Shall I take the package?
No, no.
- We'll take it with us.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
And in the end, he killed her.
- Yes.
She was kidnapped, for 72
hours abused and then strangled.
Her name was Mareike Menadt.
How old was she?
- 16.
Jörg Albrecht got 15 years.
In prison, he participated in
a re- socialization program.
He had good behavior, a
favorable social prognosis.
Why did he serve his sentence
in full?
Because there was a
second person in the room.
The one who filmed everything.
The one whose name Jörg
Albrecht didn't want to reveal.
The one who might also have
committed Mareike's murder.
That's why they didn't grant him
early release despite his good behavior.
Can I just interrupt?
- Mhm.
Ms. Bittner is waiting in the office.
Jörg Albrecht's probation officer.
We were scheduled at exactly nine
to meet at the prison.
I was late,
he was no longer there.
The gatekeeper told me that he
got into a car with a woman.
At nine.
But he doesn't answer his phone.
That's when you
reported it to the police.
No, but when I was
about to leave yesterday,
my car had
a punctured tire.
I only noticed it
after a kilometer.
What's the gatekeeper's name?
- Mr. Engel.
The girl's relatives?
- Her parents.
Simone and Frank Menadt.
He's a doctor, and they are also
the private prosecutors.
Mareike Mendt was her only child.
No aunts, no uncles.
Could they have known that Jörg
Albrecht was being released yesterday?
Co-prosecutors are informed
of the date of release.
Mhm.
What's the address?
- Sorry?
The address.
- Uh ... Im Schöttinger 4.
Thank you.
(Bird cawing)
(Music: "It Takes A Lot To
Know A Man"" by Damien Rice)
"What are you so afraid to lose?"
"What is it you're thinking
that will happen if you do?"
"What are you so afraid to lose?"
"What is it you're thinking
that will happen if you do?"
"What are you so afraid to lose?"
"What is it you're thinking
that will happen if you do?"
(Doorbell)
Bootz, Criminal Police, Stuttgart.
This is my colleague Lannert.
Are you Mr. and Mrs. Mendt?
- Yes.
Jörg Albrecht has been murdered.
I can't believe we'd live to see this!
May we come in for a moment?
- Of course.
Come this way.
Here, straight ahead.
My wife will show you to the living room.
Please.
(Soft, dark music)
Please excuse
my wife's remarks.
But it is a relief for us
to know,
that Mr. Albrecht is dead.
How did it happen, who did it?
We don't know.
He was found this morning.
You were both here yesterday morning?
- You're suspecting us?
You knew
when Jörg Albrecht would be released.
That's right.
We were here.
You vouch for each other,
I assume?
Yes.
- We have to ask you that.
What would you have done
against Mr. Albrecht?
What do you mean?
He was the only one who knew
who else was involved. And did nothing.
Probably nothing.
Despite a 15-year prison sentence,
he didn't betray him.
Today he probably wouldn't
have done it either.
He didn't betray him,
because the detectives back then
weren't persistent enough.
They should have kept asking longer.
We had lost Mareike.
The authorities back then, the ...
We even had to tell them,
that there must have been
a second man.
How did you know that?
- From the film.
Do you have a film?
Can we see it?
Simone, I can't.
Yes ... Yes, fine, then ...
Come, I'll show you.
(Soft, atmospheric music)
Where did you get those?
They're circulating online.
They tortured my daughter...
... for three days and nights
straight.
Yes, maybe, uh, could you
uh, take a look at the pictures?
We already know the photos.
- Oh, you know the photos?
Take another look, maybe
it will help you with the work.
We already took a good look
at you.
We would be interested in
this film.
They tortured my daughter
for three days and nights.
Yes.
- Just take another look.
They abused her.
And I wasn't there for her.
She must have wondered why
her father and I weren't there.
Why we weren't helping her!
And then they killed her!
I wish I could have endured that
for her.
And then they ...
... those animals put the
photos up online, sold them.
Strangers took pleasure
in these images.
Wasn't that stopped?
- Yes, of course.
Of course, they've tried that. They've
had the content blocked again and again ...
... Over and over, it gets blocked.
But the internet never forgets.
And eventually there's another one
of those ... One of those providers in ...
... Russia or in Togo.
And eventually the ones who
bought the pictures re-upload them.
To ... Yes, to trade them.
For other photos.
Like pirated copies, that's
how the police explained it to us.
She also said she was
powerless against it.
And, um ... this film?
Ms. Mendt, can
we take a look at it?
Can you please take
your hands off it?
Please?
Don't touch my computer!
You wanted to show us this film.
- Wait!
Here ...
At second 35 ...
the image moves.
They didn't just kill Mareike.
They destroyed three lives.
(Soft music)
That's when the camera moved.
Thank you for your time and the infor-
mation about the online businesses.
You are the first.
- The first what?
Since the trial. The murderer
was reported on constantly.
But the last reporter only wanted
to photograph Mareike's room.
And stole photos.
- Yes?
That was 15 years ago ...
_ "Vogt_"
We haven't yet finished
Mr. Albrecht's autopsy.
But I can say two things
with certainty.
Someone gave him an
IV in the elbow crease.
"And he died of an
overdose of pentobarbital."
" Veterinarians use that
to put them to sleep, right?
It used to be a sedative.
Not everyone woke back up.
Who can easily get their hands on it?
- Anyone with manufacturer access.
"Pharmacists, maybe.
Veterinarians for sure."
Doctors?
- Yes, too.
Okay. Understood.
Thank you, Mr. Vogt.
(Doorbell)
Mr. Mendt,
you practiced as a doctor?
Yes.
- I'm placing you under temporary custody.
On suspicion of murder
of Jörg Albrecht.
He was killed with a lethal
dose of pentobarbital.
Ah. May I get my coat?
- Go ahead.
(Quiet, atmospheric music)
We'll be right back.
(She sighs.)
Do you have children?
Not anymore.
And you?
You think I can't fathom
what's going on inside you.
But I have a daughter, too.
She asked me
if she could go to her first
sleepover.
When can I contact my
lawyer?
In the President's office.
Does Claudia Bittner mean anything to you?
- No. Did she kill Albrecht?
I understand.
There is no greater pain
than the loss of a child.
If one tries to imagine
an increa- se in the pain,
one thinks it would be so great,
that it should kill you instantly.
Unbearable.
But then the pain comes,
and you endure it.
And it comes from the certainty
that the man
who tore Mareike out of this life,
who destroyed everything
that Mareike could have become,
that this man, after prison,
gets something
that is denied to you and your daughter
: a fresh start.
A new life,
a new chance.
And that is unbearable.
That has tormented you and your wife.
- Yes, it has.
To put it bluntly,
The justice system, the media - everyone
cared about Albrecht.
For his placement,
his psychological assessment,
his social prognosis.
He underwent
psychiatric sessions
and was able to work through everything.
But both of you
were left on your own.
It was made clear to you that
society didn't care,
how you coped with
your loss.
Yes.
Are you a supporter
of the death penalty?
There is a common correlation
between education level
and attitude toward it.
The less educated,
the greater the support.
The mobile carrier's
analysis.
Both phones have been
unused and static for two days.
When is your lawyer coming?
- Probably stuck in traffic.
The surveillance camera in front of the prison
doesn't help us either.
Why?
- You only see a car pull up
and Jörg Albrecht get in.
- The license plate?
It's been obscured.
- Thanks.
Yes ...
I'll take it from here.
You knew
when Jörg Albrecht would be released.
You slashed the tires of his
probation officer
and kidnapped him.
- No.
I don't even know her!
I believe that to this day
you still suffer greatly
from having lost your daughter.
You have my full understanding.
But your suffering does not elevate
you above the law.
As an uninvolved party,
that's a very simple perspective.
You took the law
into your own hands.
You killed your daughter's
murderer. Out of revenge.
But above all, you wanted
the name of the other man.
The one who was filming.
And there was only one
person, who knew it: Albrecht.
He has not voluntarily withdrawn
himself from it. They had to kidnap him.
And now that Albrecht is dead,
you will know this name.
- No.
It is entirely up to you.
Tell me the name of the co-
conspirator, and I will have him arrested.
He will come before a court
and be convicted.
Dangerous, what you are planning.
- You would do that for me?
I would do that for you.
- Danger is imminent.
The question is, for whom.
Who should testify to the complicity
of the man,
when the only one who could do it
is dead?
Mr. Mendt,
we always find something.
An eyelash, a hair, skin flakes,
something - we'll find something.
Unfortunately, I don't
know the name of this man.
Hello.
- Hello.
Mr. Bootz, do you have a moment?
- Yes.
I know.
You can't put the man
in pretrial detention.
Your suspicion doesn't hold up.
- I'm well aware of that.
(quietly:) Okay.
Stuttgart District Attorney's Office.
I am Emilia Alvarez.
Frank Mendt.
Your arrest
was not justified.
Commissioner Bootz
is taking you home.
I'm sorry about the circumstances.
- Thank you, I'd rather walk.
Goodbye.
(quietly:) Come on, let's go.
(Tense music)
You shouldn't have let him go.
No.
You could have held him for 48 hours.
What would we have gained?
- Time.
Only to a limited extent.
We would have had to tail him
fo r the rest of his life,
to stop him from taking the law
into his own hands.
Now we can directly
stop him from doing something foolish
and catch the second man.
He goes to the taxis.
- "Yes, I see him."
Hello.
Reinhard, you're taking one too!
Pursue him!
"Quick, he's already leaving!"
(Engine is started.)
(Tense music)
He's in a taxi heading south
on his way.
Then he's not heading home.
- "Doesn't look like it."
"Where are you?"
- I'll be right there.
Reinhard, fall
back, I'll take over.
Okay. Understood.
Ms. Lothar, yes?
Milena Lothar, yes.
- You're a trainee detective?
Do you have a boyfriend?
- Daniel.
Don't lose track of him
while chasing down criminals.
(Barking)
Oh, we're getting visitors.
Hello.
Lannert.
- Hello.
Damn.
Weigert.
Visitors?
- No, nobody was here.
She's not out either?
- Nope.
Keeps wandering around
the house: lights on, lights off.
(Tense music)
They go where Mendt goes.
Discreetly.
I'm always there, don't
worry. Watch your back, clear?
It looks like he's
taking the funicular.
(Reinhard:) "Inheritance Chaser Express."
- I beg your pardon?
"He means the cable
car to the cemetery."."
He's probably visiting Mareike's grave.
- "Could very well be."
"Can you hear me, Reinhard?"
- Affirmative.
If Mendt gets on, stay
below in case he comes back.
"Mrs. Lothar, you're riding up."
- And you?
"See you up there."
- "He's on board."
"Colleague is following."
(Murmuring, signal tone)
Hm! What's this going to be?
- No idea.
(Tense music)
Not exactly "Lights On, Lights Off"!
(Ominous music)
Mrs. Mendt!
Just went into a flower shop.
(She chucks.)
And, what did you say then?
Heading to the cemetery right
now, I'm following. Where are you?
"I'm on my way."
Super!
When did you last see her?
And if she's hiding?
- And where? In the washing machine?
Maybe she's shopping.
- Of course, she said:
Then I'll sneak
through the garden to the supermarket.
Gentlemen, surveillance doesn't mean
sitting on your ass in the car!
When did you last
see her?
Oh, the light just turned on!
Hopefully yours did too!
Those are timer switches!
When did you last
see her?
She was upstairs in the room once,
that was ... half an hour.
Issue a missing person alert
for Simone Mendt immediately.
Immediately!
- Yes.
(Tense music)
Have you lost him?
- Yes.
He turned the
corner and was gone.
Shit!
(Phone rings.)
Shit ...
- Hello?
It's me. Simone Mendt
has gone missing.
"Be careful that the same thing
doesn't happen to Mr. Mendt!"
It just happened.
- Shit!
What was it? Weigert and Teufel?
- Man, hey ...
Man, fuck!
(Soft, dark music)
So?
Yeah, I've got something.
Mr. Mendt called a lawyer
from here earlier.
Can you get the number?
- Yeah, sure.
This is everything we have
in connection with Jörg Albrecht.
So, where things stand.
The Mendts are being sought
nationwide.
The man involved in the abuse
probably has no idea
that his life is in danger.
And somewhere here is the clue
about this second man.
We should be faster than them.
The colleagues from back then
focused on the members of the
biker club.
Okay, let's narrow it down.
Albrecht spent two years in
prison for animal cruelty and assault.
A year before the murder
of Mareike he got out.
And he joined the Devils.
He met this guy in prison.
Stefan Freund.
The number Mendt
dialed, is his own landline.
He called his wife.
- And warned her.
You tricked both of us.
- That strengthens the suspicion of murder.
One more thing: I found in the ashtray
a small reflection
from a hand of the person
who filmed.
The computer still needs a bit of time.
- Let me know.
Albrecht's new friends
are the Devils.
Which one of them would
film an act of abuse
and even putting him online,
to make money out of it?
One of his new friends.
That's the biker club Devils.
Michael Kurzenberger got
drunk and drove to his death.
Stefan Freund keeps
turning up for drug offenses.
Lives on Hartz IV, here in Stuttgart.
Joachim Huber now has
a bar in Untertürkheim.
Matthias Lösel died in
Brittany in a knife fight.
I've got something!
Okay, take a look at the ashtray.
Do you see that?
- Yes...
On the ashtray, I found the
reflection of a man's hand.
I interpolated the whole
thing, it took about two hours.
Here's the result.
A turtle or something ...
- Yes.
(Soft, tense music)
There.
Stefan Freund.
(Dark music)
(Low conversation)
Bye, Lena. See you tomorrow.
Stefan Freund?
- Yes.
My name is Lannert, Homicide
Stuttgart. My colleague Bootz.
May we see
your hands for a moment?
(He sniffs.)
We're taking you into
protective custody now.
Protective custody? Why?
Mareike Mendt, does
that mean anything to you?
No.
The colleagues are getting things
from the apartment. Come with me.
(Siren)
Thank you.
(Engine is started.)
(Tense music)
Hi!
(Door is closed.)
(Radio:) "... there may be
occasional sleet tonight."
Maja?
Leaving the lights on everywhere ...
Are you hungry?
I made you dinner!
Yeah, I can see it! Wow!
(Music from the radio)
Whoa, that looks delicious!
Do you think you can send
me to the party like this?
You really are something!
Change your clothes, I'll drive you.
- Anna's mother is driving us.
I hadn't even said yes yet!
(Doorbell)
That's Anna!
- Hey, um...
Yes?
- I'll pick you up tomorrow morning.
Okay, thanks!
- You're welcome.
And thanks for the food.
You're welcome!
- Take care!
I will!
(Door slams shut.)
(Calm pop music)
(Laughter, soft pop music)
Hello, Anna.
Hello.
- Is Maja still in there?
She wanted to surprise
you, with breakfast.
Oh, I see? When did she leave?
- Half past six?
Half past six?
Weird...
She wanted to go straight home.
- Yes. Isn't she at home?
Nah, but that doesn't mean a thing.
I'll give her a call.
(Man:) "Yeah?"
- Who's there?
"You know who's
here, Mr. Bootz."
(Eerie music)
Where is my daughter?
- "She's with me."
"She's sleeping."
- What do you want?
"Stefan Freund."
"I'm checking in."
(Dial tone)
Shit ...
(He breathes rapidly.)
This is Basti. I need a cell
phone trace immediately.
My daughter,
who ... lost her phone.
It's just gone.
Can you do that?
(Atmospheric,
tense music)
(Distant siren)
The first signal came about 20
minutes ago, right here in Wangen.
The second one five
minutes ago, near Villa Berg.
And since then, your
daughter's phone has been dead.
It has apparently
changed hands.
Let me know immediately
when it stops moving.
Yeah, but I've got other things to do.
- Hey, this is extremely important!
There's sensitive data on it, okay?
So just do it.
Morning.
- Good morning.
Anything new from the Mends?
- No.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Do you have any new leads
from the Mends?
Uh, no. But I've
raised the alert level.
What?
Raised? Why raise it?
- What, why?
Because one of them or both
of them murdered Jörg Albrecht.
But that's not even
proven yet.
Why did the two of
them disappear yesterday?
It's as good as proven.
The forensic team searched
the Mends' house last night.
They found hair and skin particles in the
basement and on the stairs.
Jörg Albrecht was definitely there.
It seems to me an undercover search
would be more sensible.
Aha ...
Apparently, the Mends have launched their
private crusade for revenge.
They murdered Albrecht.
But if he told them,
that it's Stefan Freund,
before he died,
the one they're looking for.
Then the story is
over here.
We have Freund. Sooner or later
the Mends will fall into our net.
So they're no longer a threat?
They never were to the public.
They did what they wanted to do.
Nothing suggests
that they're going on a rampage now.
But they're probably murderers.
- Exactly.
That's why I'm concerned
about the risk to bystanders.
The Mendts are on the run
for the first time in their lives.
That is real psychological
stress for them.
Anything could happen.
Especially when ...
... Officer Norbert from Klein
Gartbach wants to arrest them.
Hold on,
what's this really about?
What I'm trying to say is:
I just want us to scale this down to
a covert search.
The manhunt is active,
but whoever knows anything about Mends,
they call us here.
I see no problem with that.
- Mhm.
Then I'll arrange it.
Maybe they're already
abroad.
No, they're still here.
In the Stuttgart area.
They can't just
vanish into thin air.
They have to eat, sleep,
shop. Contact other people.
They have no idea
about living on the run.
They'll make mistakes.
Leave traces.
We can take another look
around their house. Shall we?
You go. I'll look into everything else
: bank details, phone connections,
social circle.
That way we're more efficient.
Can you convince a judge
that
we can get access
to the accounts?
That's already been done.
I'll press further.
So, see you then.
- Let me know if you find anything.
Yeah.
Everything good with you?
(He sighs.)
(Distant siren)
(Quiet, tense music)
Sorry about earlier.
Anything new?
Yeah.
- Yeah?
Here. This is new.
Killesberg ...
- Mhm.
And now, in this moment?
It's over. Sebastian, what's
actually going on with you?
(Mobile phone rings.)
Everything's fine.
I have to take this real quick.
I'll call back in a bit.
Hello?
- (Woman:) "Sebastian?"
"It just rained. We're already
on our way back today."
What?
- "Do you want me to bring Maja over?"
"I'm making flatbread.
You're of course invited."
"Sebastian?"
- Yes, yes, yes. I, um ...
I'm still on it. Um ...
Where are you now?
"At Moritz's place. He and Henri
won't be coming until tomorrow."
I see. I ... I'll stop by.
(Quiet, tense music)
I'll call you.
(Quiet, uneasy music)
(Fast music)
(Honking)
(Mobile phone rings.)
Yes? Hello?
(Mendt:) "So, how does it feel?"
"When you no longer
lecture another father
on what right and wrong are?"
"On
whether his suffering permits him
to place himself above the law?"
- Not good.
It doesn't feel good.
"In an hour I'll tell you
where to deliver Freund."
"And you can have your daughter
back unharmed."
"The chance I never had."
"It's entirely up to you."
"From now on I'll only be
calling from a prepaid phone."
But what ... what will you
do to Mr. Freund?
Execute him? Take his life?
"My daughter was ...
abused through all of her body orifices."
"Had she not been strangled,
she would have died from the internal
bleeding."
"This unspeakable martyrdom
lives in our minds."
"And my wife and I.
It governs our daily life."
"It occupies us day and night."
"For 15 years. Now I'm going to
put an end to this torment."
I'm sorry. I'm truly
sorry, Mr. Mendt.
I know, it's terrible, I ...
But ...
If I don't give you a friend
and you take my daughter from me,
what are you going to do?
Do you and your wife simply want
to keep a marriage going? How?
"I certainly don't want that."
"Then we're leaving too."
(Tense music)
"In an hour, yes."
(Bird call)
(Soft, calm music)
(Doorbell)
You're quick. The flame
pie is not ready yet.
Your guy isn't here, is he?
- What? No.
And Henri? Where is Henri?
- No.
I did say
they're not coming until tomorrow.
What's going on?
(He's breathing hard.)
What happened to Maja?
She's been kidnapped.
- What?
By a married couple
who had a daughter of their own.
The... Fifteen years ago she was
kidnapped, she...
... was abused
by two perpetrators.
Then one of them got out,
and the one who...
They took revenge on him.
They want the other one, but
we have him, that's why they have Maja.
When did this happen?
- This morning? I'm not exactly sure.
Maja wanted to go to
this sleepover party,
and I actually said no.
She ended up
talking me into it.
She was allowed to go, I wanted
to pick her up in the morning.
And she was gone.
Did they let you
talk to her?
No, but she's doing fine,
I know that.
How do you know that?
- Because I know it!
How do they even know about Maja?
Because I told him, of course.
You told him?
- Yeah, he had asked me.
Because he also had a daughter,
and I said, I have a daughter too.
Shit, I gotta go!
- I'm coming with you.
You're not coming with me!
- Of course I'm coming.
No!
- Am I supposed to just sit here, or what?
That's not possible! You can't
come with me! It doesn't work!
That's not possible! They're
pulling me off the case!
I can't do anything
anymore, take care of you.
This other offender.
Can't you just swap them out, right?
W... What, how?
Yeah, swap them out.
- Yeah, but then he's dead.
He's dead!
- And what do you want to do then?
What would you even do?
You'd just hand the man over to them
for your daughter, wouldn't you?
There's no way you would,
not for even one second ...
There has to be another way! Should I
put a bullet in his head?
What are you going to do?
- I'll save her.
I'll pull it off.
I'll find a way.
I'll call you.
(Dark music)
(Engine noise, barking)
(Tense music)
I'm up here!
Sebastian!
Did you find anything?
They've set up her daughter's room
so perfectly,
as if she were to come home
any moment now.
They're not done yet.
They haven't come to
terms with their grief yet.
That will only happen
once Freund is convicted.
What's going on?
(He's breathing heavily.)
I, um ...
You have to promise
me something, Thorsten.
You need to keep this to yourself,
okay?
I don't want to be
pulled off this case.
The Mendts have kidnapped Maja.
What?
- Yes. They kidnapped Maja.
That's not true, is it?
- It is.
You've got to be kidding!
They want me to hand over
Stefan Freund in exchange for her.
Then they'll let her go.
- This can't be right!
But it is!
- Do you know where she might be?
M-m. No.
And when?
They, um....
Forty-five minutes.
Then he'll check in again.
That's why we're not going public.
Nobody knows what they're planning.
If they're under pressure,
anything could happen.
Or some dumb cop
shoots at them.
Who's going to tell me
where my daughter is? Shit!
We need a full-scale manhunt now.
- No!
No full-scale manhunt,
are you out of your mind?
How are we supposed to find them on our own?
- I thought that ...
... that maybe you would
... Fuck, I don't know!
In any other case it'd
be a full-scale manhunt.
This is no ordinary case!
- Yeah, I know!
We need to go to Nika.
There must be a lead.
If Mendt wants to have
Freund, he has to show his face.
So, come on.
Come on, let's go now!
(He sighs.)
Hey, any news?
- Not yet. Any with you?
No.
The PC and the credit cards haven't been used,
and the phones are dead. Unfortunately.
There's a problem.
What is it?
The Mends want Stefan Freund,
to get their revenge on him.
Because they can't get their
hands on him, they've been ...
... they have kidnapped Sebastian's
daughter and are extorting him.
What?
- Are you out of your mind?
What is this?
- Stop it!
Stop it!
- For God's sake!
You don't have a
daughter left to lose!
Pull yourself together!
- Come back!
Mr. Bootz, please! Please!
You promised me!
- I never promised you anything!
Just stop it!
Remove Mr. Bootz
from the case due to bias.
You promised me!
- I didn't say a thing!
Cut the crap!
- Is that true?
You foul woman!
Are you insane?
You are Maya's father,
you ... You are biased!
You can't handle this case.
- Why not?
(He sniffs.)
Hand over your service
weapon and badge immediately.
You are temporarily
relieved of duty.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
The badge.
- I don't have it with me.
I don't have my badge
with me, it's at home.
You can send someone.
You stay here and help
with the investigation.
As a father, not as a detective!
We need a photo for the manhunt.
No manhunt! I won't allow
it! It puts them in danger!
You're putting them in danger!
Only a large-scale manhunt will help!
Someone must have
seen the Mendts or her.
Please, no manhunt! The Mendts
don't know a thing about that.
They're under so much
pressure! Don't do this!
Mr. Bootz!
If a man comes to you whose daughter
has been kidnapped, what do you do?
Fuck ...
(sobbing:) What the hell is going on!
If a man were to come to you whose
daughter has just been kidnapped,
you would immediately
launch a massive search!
That you're not doing it now,
because you assess the danger to
your daughter so differently,
because you're the one affected, shows
how right it is
not to leave the decision
up to you.
What about the photo?
Do you have one, or should I
take it out of the desk?
(Sobbing)
Do we have any leads
on where she is?
No.
- And where are the Mendts?
They'll only show themselves
once we hand Freund over to them.
Okay.
You're releasing the manhunt
data including Mrs. Banovic now.
Age, height, and clothing.
Also for the Mendts. Reasons for the
manhunt: Murder and child abduction.
Out immediately,
to all departments.
Immediately to regional and
national TV news.
Also the online press, radio.
To all airport staff,
taxi drivers.
I want that within an hour
everyone knows who Maja Bootz is.
You can put everyone
in the building to work.
If we don't find Sebastian's daughter
and the Mends,
we'll have to stage
a handover.
And carry it out with full force.
- Yes, I'm counting on you.
Sebastian, I need
the biometric data.
Brown eyes, brown hair,
Height: 1.52.
Mr. Bootz! Mr. Bootz, please,
the search data!
Please!
(Soft, tense music)
It was right,
what you did.
Let's hope so.
(Radio:) "The weather for Württemberg,
from the Alps to the Main."
"Snow or sleet,
lots of clouds,
at minus one to plus three degrees."
"Another important appeal
from the Stuttgart Police."
"Maja Bootz, 13, is wanted,
brown hair, brown eyes,
black jeans and a red puffer jacket."
"In a few minutes I'll have
the event tips for you."
"SWR3 until twelve -
the morning show!"
"At the microphone Michael Reufsteck,
hello. We're collecting backups ..."
(Typing)
She's 13, right?
(Dark music)
(Typing)
Today at Mendt's
I noticed something else,
that might help us further.
In a vacation photo
a motorhome can be seen.
It could be that they still
have it and are on the road with it.
I'll call the vehicle registration
office.
(Door closed.)
(Quiet, oppressive music)
(Bird cries)
Lannert.
- Karle.
I'm glad you could make it.
I need a man around forty.
Hand-to-hand training,
single. He'll be Stefan Freund.
I know someone for that.
The two of them are
in a state of emergency.
The world, they think, has
taken no note of their pain.
And now they go
and set a beacon.
Show the world the pain,
that they have suffered.
Now the world shall suffer.
That they drag a girl to her death,
they shut it out.
They even have to.
They don't want to kill Maja,
they want Stefan Freund.
But if we think
we can outsmart them,
because they won't harm my colleague's daughter,
then they will
give us a very harsh wake-up call.
They already felt
betrayed by the world.
They won't let that
happen to them again.
So the final rescue shot?
- Absolutely not.
Fire authorization only
on my express orders.
And if so, then only hand or legs.
We need to find the girl,
and if we kill Mendt,
then we might
never find out.
Then the hand is gone.
What do you
normally use it for?
Against misunderstandings.
(He sighs.)
S, I, Z, 2306.
Great, thanks!
Thorsten was right:
They have a motorhome.
Okay, so.
We're looking for a vehicle
with the license plate SIZ-2306.
(Cell phone rings.)
SIZ-2306, the owners are Mendt.
- No problem.
(Suspenseful music)
Yes?
- (Mendt:) "Do you have him?"
Not yet. But I'll get him.
At 12.30 I'm standing by
for exactly two minutes ...
"... on the Max-Eyth-Steg."
"Do you understand?"
- Yes, I understand.
"Good."
We still have about 20 minutes
to find the motorhome.
Okay ...
Mendt has checked in.
He'll be there in 20 minutes
at the Max-Eyth-Steg.
The car is in the underground parking.
A Mr. Karle from the SEK is inside.
It will be Stefan Freund.
And that's your plan?
- You drive with Karle there,
you can deliver him, but you must
insist on seeing Maja.
No visual contact, no exchange.
- And then?
Then you insist on contact.
If not at the Steg, then somewhere else.
On contact: engage.
There's no other way.
Is there a catch?
- No!
Once we find the RV,
we'll hit both locations.
Your plan is shit. What if
they happen to have a photo?
Then they'll see
we're fucking with them!
Then my daughter's dead,
Thorsten.
Then tell me how you'd do it,
and we'll do it exactly that way.
So, what's your plan?
Because you don't have one.
You want to turn in a friend.
You might as well just shoot him
in the head yourself.
I want my daughter back!
You should know how that feels!
Yes! But if you hand that man
over,
you're knowingly sending
him to his death.
At least not my daughter.
Yeah, exactly. That's your plan.
I'm downstairs.
I shouldn't have told you.
(Soft, tense music)
"All five positions: clear to engage!"
"Two in position."
"Decoy in sight."
"Target at twelve o'clock.
Is that Frank Mendt?"
Confirm, that's Frank Mendt.
"Target carries in the
left hand a firearm."
"Please confirm."
- "Yes, correct."
"Could take him down for good."
- "Absolutely not!"
Fire authorization is
given exclusively by me.
"Understood."
(Tense music)
Meeting point.
Is that Stefan Freund?
- Yes.
I want to see now
my daughter.
My wife is bringing you
your daughter now.
(Cough)
No! Wait!
That's not Stefan Freund.
That's someone from the police.
I'm sorry.
(Fast music)
Please don't do that.
(whispers:) We'll see each other
tonight. You bring me the right one.
Of course.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry!
The man is free to leave.
No one follows.
The man is clear to leave.
- (Screams:) Shit!
Damn it!
(Dark, pulsing music)
That was an absolute shit plan.
It wasn't a shit plan,
it just didn't work.
If anything were to happen
to you, Thorsten,
then we won't be
the elders anymore.
We're not anymore.
The biggest mistake was
trusting Thorsten.
I don't know what to do anymore.
(Soft music)
I'll trade him for Maja.
I'll do it.
You get him out of prison
and put him in the car.
That's all you have to do.
We can't save them
both, it's not possible.
So: put him in the car
and then walk away.
I'm not asking you for more.
(quietly:) Alright.
"We have the camper van.
It's parked in Filderstadt."
(Tense music)
Police, come in!
Hands on the table!
Sit over there!
Shit!
Lannert, Criminal Investigation, Stuttgart.
What's your license plate number?
What?
- What's your plate number?
SAB-124.
Shit! They swapped the plates!
(Dark music)
"NCK1 to Central."
- "Central, go ahead."
"The motorhome operation
in Filderstadt has failed."
"The suspects have
swapped their plates."
"Understood. Operation's over, all
units stand down."
(Tense music)
See you shortly.
"Freund [Friend], that's a funny
name for a criminal, huh?"
Yeah.
- Right, Conni?
I don't have him on the list.
- He just came up.
For a lineup.
You could always call
the prosecutor's office.
Oh, come on! Please wait here.
(Suspenseful music)
We've already heard about it.
Any new leads?
- Plenty, especially about the Mendts.
But nothing recent about it.
A priest got in touch.
Mrs. Mendt lays flowers on her
daughter's grave every Tuesday.
Today is Thursday.
Yes ... Today is Thursday.
(Dark music)
I'm in a hurry.
Watch your head.
(Phone rings.)
(Alvarez:) This is Stammheim prison.
Do you know anything about a
confrontation with Mr. Freund?
Yes, I, um ... I had
forgotten, um ...
The cybercrime colleagues
wanted to borrow him,
because of the photos,
he has published online.
But we're in touch,
in case we need him.
Okay ...
Mr. Engel, can you hear me? Yes.
Yeah, that's fine.
Absolutely.
It was right,
that you pressed the issue. Thank you.
Speak later.
Go ahead and secure those things.
You know how it's done, right?
Who should the confrontation
be with?
That's the joke
about a confrontation,
that you don't know.
I'll be right back.
(Suspenseful music)
Where is Sebastian?
Umm, he wanted to stretch his
legs, have some time to himself.
Don't lie to me!
The taxi number is 216.
Should I ask dispatch
where they picked you up?
Or are you going to tell me that
that was at Stammheim prison?
You cooked this up together.
Where is he?
I don't know.
- He's heading in for his execution!
Where is Sebastian?
It's not about him, Thorsten.
It's not about Freund,
nor about me and you.
It's about Maja, nothing else.
- Yes, it is about Maja.
If I put a search out for Sebastian,
I won't find him.
But we can help
if we find Maja,
before he hands Freund over!
So.
Did he say anything?
A meeting with Mendt, for example?
No, he didn't.
- Damn it!
I'm asking because it's pretty much
certain Maja will be nearby.
They both want to kill themselves, right?
I would say goodbye to my daughter
beforehand.
(Cell phone rings.)
Yes?
- (Mendt:) "Do you have him?"
Yes.
- "Throw your phone away."
"Your new one is at the bus stop
Schlachthof."
"The phone is lying there in the trash can."
"Press speed dial key one."
Good.
Damn!
(Soft, melancholy music)
She probably won't be coming.
The flowers are fresh.
(He sighs.)
(Tense music)
If you had children ...
So?
Would you hand the man over then?
I would step aside.
Out?
- Of it.
Out of the whole thing.
(Gloomy music)
(Menadt:) "Bootz, you're driving to
the Stuttgart Locomotive Depot now."
"Keep your phone on,
put it in your jacket pocket."
"If you switch it
off, we're gone."
"Let us know,
when you're there."
Yes.
(Suspenseful music)
(A scream) Mrs.
Mendt, this is the police.
Where is the girl?
Where is Maja?
Tell us, where the girl is!
(She screams.)
Mrs. Mendt!
(shouting:) Mrs. Mendt!
You're a mother
too, just like me!
(She groans.)
Stay calm!
(quietly:) Yes ... Yes ...
Here.
That was my wife. And
that was Leni, my daughter.
At the hospital, they told me
both of them would survive!
They didn't make it. I
know what that means!
I know how it feels. Mrs. Mendt!
Tell us where Maja is! Please!
I know there's no
cure for the pain.
But I don't want my colleague
to go through the same thing.
Please tell us,
where the girl is.
Please!
Yes ...
Shit!
Ms. Mendt!
- Ms. Mendt! Shit!
(Ms. Mendt coughs and chokes.)
Ms. Mendt!
Oh God, shit!
(Gurgling)
Get the ambulance, now!
Ms. Mendt! Ms. Mendt!
Shit! Shit!
Ms. Mendt?
Nika! Nika, Nika, Nika!
- Can you hear me?
Nika, we need an emergency
location on number 0147-843231.
As fast as possible!
Hurry up!
(Suspenseful music)
"Yes?"
- I'm here.
Good. Can you see car
number three, the green one?
Green car ... Okay ...
"That's the frontmost car."
"
Ah, I can see it.
Good, step behind the car.
Now I can see you.
Come toward me.
(Suspenseful music)
Where is Freund?
In the car, in handcuffs.
Put down your service weapon,
slowly.
I ... I don't have a service weapon.
Mr. Mendt, I ...
I'm removing myself from the equation.
I can't give you Freund.
You'll have to
find someone else.
Then your daughter dies.
But not
because I won't give you someone,
but because you'll kill her.
It won't help you.
It won't bring you any closer to Freund.
You'll also have
killed a little girl.
Where is the car?
- The car? That ...
The car is in the yard
of a police station.
You're not getting to it.
I don't know what I should
do, do you understand?
I can't live with not saving my
daughter.
But I can't
be a friend to you either.
That can't be!
I'm sorry.
Can you help me?
(Tense music)
Please help me! Please!
- Yes, yes.
Show me,
how much you love your daughter.
What?
Your life
for your daughter's life.
(Driving music)
Show me.
(Suspenseful music)
I have your word?
- Yes!
(Clicking)
The RV is at the garden center.
East Business Park.
It's time now.
(Gunshot)
(Shrill whistle)
Oh God!
(Eerie music)
The RV is at the garden center
in the East Business District.
At the garden center in
the East Business District ...
(Eerie, atmospheric music)
How are you doing?
I'm fine.
I'm sorry for what I said
about your daughter.
(Eerie music)
SWR 2015